garden.org 2018-09-07

# Privacy Policy - Garden.org

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Garden.org we have a few fundamental principles: 

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:

It is Garden.org's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Garden.org collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Garden.org’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Garden.org’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Garden.org may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Garden.org also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Garden.org does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Garden.org's website choose to interact with Garden.org in ways that require Garden.org to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Garden.org gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a membership to provide a username and optionally their email address. Those who engage in transactions with Garden.org are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Garden.org collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with Garden.org. Garden.org does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Garden.org discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Garden.org's behalf or to provide services available at Garden.org's website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Garden.org's website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Garden.org will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Garden.org discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Garden.org believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Garden.org, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Garden.org username and have supplied your email address, Garden.org may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, notify you of a private message, or simply to keep you up to date with what's going on with Garden.org and our products. We primarily use our various forums and newsletter to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a Contact Us message or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Garden.org takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Garden.org uses cookies to help Garden.org identify and track visitors, their usage of Garden.org website, and their website access preferences. Garden.org visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Garden.org's website, with the drawback that certain features of Garden.org's website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Ads

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Garden.org and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Payments

We use Stripe for payment, analytics, and other business services. Stripe collects identifying information about the devices that connect to its services. Stripe uses this information to operate and improve the services it provides to us, including for fraud detection. You can learn more about Stripe and read its privacy policy at https://stripe.com/privacy. 

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Garden.org may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Garden.org's sole discretion. Garden.org encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
